Iphone Developer

Amol Gaikwad

amolgaikwad1323@gmail.com

Mobile No: 9890561135

CAREER Objective

I aspire to work in an organization that provides ample exposure and opportunities to grow and excel in my skills and to make meaningful contributions towards the objectives of the organization. Seeking to work under challenging and growing environment where my technical and analytical skills are used in full potential.

EXPERIENCE SUMMARY

Software Engineer: Optra systems pvt Limited, Pune (http://www.optrasystems.com/) Involved in design, development of Mobile application. (8 Months, Sept 2012 to till date)

Analyst Programmer: Indecomm Global Services, Pune (<u>www.indecommglobal.com</u>), Involved in design, development of iOS application. (11 months Oct 2011 to Sept 2012)

Web Developer: Anuva Technologies. Pune (<u>www.anuvatech.com</u>), involved in design and development of ecommerce and oscommerce websites. Also worked on mobile compatible websites as well as iOS application. (18 months, Mar 2010 to Sept 2011)

IOS work experience: 2.0 + yrs

Total work experience: 3.0 + yrs.

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Design & development of mobile application.
- Ability to demonstrate integrity while successfully managing work demands and pressure.
- Manage, participate or advise on technical environment improvement projects.
- Experience in working with a high-paced, collaborative, team-based project environment.
- Develop project with owned skills

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Operating Systems: Macintosh, Linux-Mint, Ubuntu, MS Windows XP
- Languages: C, Objective-C, CPP
- Web-Programming: PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS
- **RDBMS:** Oracle, Mysql, Sqlite
- Core Skills: iOS Application Development
- iOS Skills: Cocoa Touch
- Mobile Development Tools : Titanium, Phone Gap

•

DermLink (iPhone)

DermLink.md is a HIPAA compliant application that enables remote diagnosis of any skin problem. Now you can get fast and convenient 24/7 access to a board certified U.S. based dermatologist from the comfort of your home or office. Simply take a picture of your rash, mole, hair, nails, or any spot on your skin, answer a few short questions about it, and receive a diagnosis and prescription within 24 hours or less.

ShiftGen(iPhone, iPad & Android)

ShiftGen is a workforce management tool for any business that requires shift based scheduling for workers. Accessible through mobile device. ShiftGen provides roster management, scheduling, schedule management, messaging, time and attendance and payroll management solutions.

- Mobile Messaging
- Split Shifts
- Clock In/Clock Out On Premises
- 🔁 Overtime Tracking
- Wide Range of User Privileges
- One Tap Historical Reports
- Work Hours and Payroll Reports
- Time and Attendance at Work
- P Comprehensive Reporting

We have used TITANIUM for this application. ShiftGen app is compatible almost all devices.

MobiPath (iPad)

MobiPath™ is a unique platform to support Lab data, Pathologists data as well as Patient data which smoothens the work flow. Built with all security standards, MobiPath™ is tested to meet 75% code coverage standards. We have developed this app for pathologist. Using this app pathologist can create case, he can edit the case.

We used SalesForcs native SDK for this application.

John Deere (iPhone and iPad Application)

List of Application

- 1. Z900A ZTrak™ PRO Mower (iPad and iPhone).
- 2. 8R & 8RT Tractors.
- 3. 9R & 9RT Tractors.
- 4. 7R Series Tractors.
- 5. 70 Series Tractors.

- 6. 900 Balers.
- 7. 1-Series.
- 8. 6RR2.
- 9. 6RR4

Project Details

: John Deere wants to develop a series of iOS compatible Apps on its various products for its dealer sales persons globally. The Apps will facilitate the sales persons in conducting products walkthrough with the customer during the pre-sales process.

An App will facilitate a product walkthrough in the following ways:

A comprehensive product information source that can be used as a job aid by the sales person during the pre-sales process
An aid that enables sales persons to do value selling
An interactive product brochure that can be used to communicate the product features and benefits to the customer
A tool that will provide the feel for the product to the customer in such a way that the customer is inspired to make a purchase.

Instead of developing all the Apps together, John Deere first wanted to develop iOS compatible App, that will function as a pilot for the rest of the product Apps.

360 Degree Section: This section provides **360-Degree view** and **Panorama** View of Tractor model.

Generalized Framework with XML approach: The Framework is designed and developed in such a way that, if you change in XML file for any type of content, it will reflect in Template. E.g If you want to update your table view cells, adding buttons, showing specific information view on specific button tap, you will need to make changes in that Template xml file only and everything will get updated in template UI. This generalized approach designed to help in to providing base for all other John Deere applications which has same templates with different contents.

Role	: Developer

Edwards Life Sciences (EV1000 System eLearning Course)

Project Details

: In this course, you will begin with an overview of the different types of cannulae developed by Edwards. Then, you will learn how to sell Edwards Protection Cannulae. After that, you will learn in detail about our premium arterial cannulae - the EZ Glide aortic perfusion cannula, the OptiSite arterial cannula, and the EMBOL-X Glide Protection System. The next lesson will focus on the Trim-Flex venous cannula, and finally you will learn about some key retrograde cannulae, including the RC014, RC2014, and the PLD014MIBH. In each lesson, there are assessment questions that test your understanding of the concepts taught. You will need to score 80 percent or more in the overall assessment to pass this course. The purpose of this course is to provide you with a basic overview of each cannula. You will be able to identify how each cannula is used in a surgical procedure, determine its features, and list its advantages. You can attempt any topic/Lesson through Menu provided for Completion.

Role : Developer.

WEB PROJECTS DETAILS

- 1) Opticsdome Http://www.opticsdome.com (Technologies: Magento, MySql).
- 2) Pacificorganics <u>Http://www.pacificorganics.com</u> (Technologies: Joomla, Mysql).
- 3) GetKombucha http://www.getkombucha.com (Technologies: Joomla, Mysql).
- 4) RY Recreate Yourself http://www.ry.com.au/ (Technologies: Zencart, Mysq).
- 5) Jobs4Cvs http://www.jobs4cvs.com/ (Technologies: Joomla, Mysql).
- 6) QualityGems http://www.qualitygemsbvba.com/servlet/StoreFront (Technologies: Prostore, Mysql)
- 7) Luxury Beach Wears (Technologies: Cubecart, Mysql).

EDUCATION

2009: CDAC, IACSD Pune with First Class.

2008: B.C.A. with Second Class from Pune University.

2005: **HSSC** with Second Class from Maharashtra Board.

2003: SSC with First Class from Maharashtra Board.

PERSONAL DATA

Date of Birth January 23, 1988

Permanent Address Shahapur,

Taluka Ambad, Dist -Jalna.

Jalna -431204

Current Address Flat no 11, Sidhivinayak apartment,

Shivne near shinde bridge,

Pune-23.

Passport J6275810 Valid up to 2021

SPECIAL NOTE

Proven ability to efficiently and precisely solve any problem on hand.

- Independable and flexible character, with inexhaustible stamina for work.
- Established capability to follow procedures and guidelines.
- Conceptual thinking and adapting new technology.
- Sound Mobile and Web applications Knowledge.
- Honest, Clear About Priorities, Enjoy Work.

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Represented as Class Captain during 2007 in Cricket Championship of CSIT College Chinchwad.
- Represented the CSIT College at Inter-College Championship of ASM Group Chinchwad.

Thanks

Amol V Gaikwad